Now I know for a lot of y'all you're celebrating Valentine's Day, but I'm
celebrating World Bonobo Day! What's up Bonobo? You know what? Instead of me
sitting here telling you about how bonobos have a matriarchal society,
instead of me sitting here telling you about how bonobos do not fight and have
managed to remove that from their society as a whole, instead of me telling
you about how bonobos have a bonobo handshake which is really just scissoring,
I know, just watch the video! You'll understand why I love these animals so
much and why it's so important for us to do whatever we can to protect them.
What's a bonobo? Bonobos are great apes, like humans. Have you ever heard of bonobos?
They're found only in one place, the Democratic Republic of Congo in Central
Africa. Bonobos live in the Congo rainforest, the second largest rainforest
on the planet. There's so much to love about them. They are our closest non-human
relatives. We share 98.7 percent of our DNA with bonobos. There are many
similarities between us. Like humans, bonobos are very social and they love their
children. They are intelligent and sensitive to their surroundings. They love
to eat, just like us. Their diet is mostly fruits and vegetables. Kids and even adults
love to play. Bonobos and humans have a lot in common. But bonobos are also
different from humans in important ways. They are masters of avoiding conflict.
Bonobos have evolved to avoid fighting about anything. Instead, they seek social
reassurance in times of stress. If anyone in the group is feeling stressed, someone
will give them a bonobo handshake. This socio-sexual method of conflict resolution
seems to be at the heart of their society. Bonobos are matriarchal. The females are in
charge. They band together to keep the peace in their group. Sharing is a way of
life. Bonobos feel empathy towards others. They love to share with family, friends, and
even strangers. Bonobos have a lot to teach us. They are kind, intelligent, patient, and
playful. They embody the best traits of humankind. Sadly, they're endangered. Years of poverty-driven
poaching and habitat loss in the Democratic Republic of Congo threaten bonobos with extinction.
There could be as few as 15,000 left in the wild. Since 1994, we've been working for a better
future for bonobos. Join us. You can help save our great ape relatives and their rainforest
home. Learn how. Please visit us online at friendsofbonobos.org.
Our closest relatives in the animal world. Don't say I never taught y'all nothing. Now,
go to friendsofbonobos.org and be a part of helping to save this incredible endangered creature
that is so close to us and so beautiful and we could learn so much from on how to be better
humans since we evolved from them anyway. And it seems like a lot of us left out the best
traits. Happy Bonobo Day and Valentine's Day. What better day to give some love?